Information Studies, Department of; Records ua671
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
Department of Information Studies Records1912-2004
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
State University of New York at Albany. Department of Information Studies
ua671
18.47 cubic ft.
Documents the administrative, curricular, and social activities of the Department of Information Studies from its establishment as a one year undergraduate school for librarians in 1926 through the early part of the twenty-first century.
Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
Web Archives
Access
Portions of the collection may contain recent administrative records and/or personally identifiable information. Please contact an archivist for more information.
Some files in series 1 and all of the personnel files in series 4 are restricted.
Acquisition Information
The first of these records (1926-1965) were transferred to the University Archives, M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives, by John Farley, Dean of the School of Library and Information Science, on December 16, 1974. Sometime in the late 1980's, several more items from the University Archives vertical files were combined with those previously transferred by the School of Library and Information Science. More records were received in August 2008 from Phil Eppard. 1974-2006
Administrative History
Although the Department of Information Studies officially opened in September, 1926, it traces its origins to January 5, 1887, when Melvil Dewey first opened the Columbia College School of Library Economy. Two years later, Dewey resigned from Columbia to assume the position of Director of the New York State Library in Albany. Before he left, he insured that his young library school also moved to Albany were it became an adjunct of the New York State Library and was renamed the New York State Library School. This two-year program remained in Albany until 1926 when the State Board of Regents and Columbia University's Board of Trustees combined the School with the Library School of the New York Public Library and moved it once again to Columbia University. In order to insure that a facility capable of training secondary-school librarians remained in the Capital Region, James Sullivan, the State Commissioner of Secondary Education, established a new Library School as part of the New York State College for Teachers in 1926.
However, this was not the first time that the State College had offered courses in librarianship. In 1916, the College Board of Trustees hired Elizabeth Cobb as the school's librarian and as an instructor. The 1917 College Bulletin reveals that she instructed two courses in the English Department entitled "Library Methods" and "High School Library Management." In 1921, Elizabeth Cobb became the primary instructor in the State College's new Department of Library Science, which offered in courses in "conjunction with and upon the suggestion of the New York State Library School." Cobb supervised the department until 1926, when the Department of Library Science was replaced by the new State College Library School. Martha Caroline Pritchard, herself a graduate of Dewey's New York State Library School, became the first head of the New York State College for Teachers Library School in 1926. The new one-year undergraduate curriculum consisted of a combination of classroom instruction, field work in the department's library, and organized field trips to libraries in the Capital region and in New York City. The nascent program soon received national recognition when the American Library Association's (ALA) Board of Education accredited the department as a Type III (undergraduate) library school in 1934.
By 1951 the school had expanded to a five year curriculum and in that year it offered its first Masters degree. However, six years later the school failed to gain accreditation under the 1951 standards for five-year programs adopted by the ALA. The reasons cited in the ALA's Report were that the department's small number of full-time faculty and its location in a state college rather than a university rendered it incapable of fulfilling the requirements of its new graduate program. In 1962, the same year that the New York State College for Teachers became the State University of New York at Albany, the department changed its name to the School of Library Science. The school now prepared students for jobs in school, public, and college libraries, and for careers in library education. The school's faculty were engaged in securing research and education grants, publishing, and redesigning the school's curriculum. In response to the school's advancements, the ALA re-accredited the program in 1966. The school's plan to implement a Doctoral Program in Library Science was approved by the University Senate and by the State University of New York (SUNY) central administration in 1971, but the State Education Department refused to register the new program the following year.
In 1986, the school merged with the Rockefeller College of Public Affairs and Policy. The new School of Information Science and Policy prepared its students for an assortment of careers including information systems and library management, information policy, the economics of Information, government information resource management, archives and records management, and information technology applications. In 1990, the School of Information Science and Policy and several other schools in Rockefeller College implemented a new interdisciplinary Doctoral Program in Information Science. Beginning in 1995, the school introduced the M.S. in Information Science (M.S.I.S.), a degree designed to emphasize interdisciplinary studies in information science and public policy and offer an advance internship experience. In 2000, Rockefeller College was restructured and the School of Information Science and Policy became its own school once again. This lasted until 2005, when the School of Information Science and Policy joined the new College of Computing and Information and became the Department of Information Studies.
School Names
1917-1921 English Department (two courses)
1921-1926 Department of Library Science
1926-1932 Library School
1932-1961 Department of Librarianship
1961-1962 Division of Library Science
1962-1971 School of Library Science
1971-1986 School of Library and Information Science
1986-2005 School of Information Science and Policy
2005-present Department of Information Studies
Chairmen and Deans
1917-1926 Mary Elizabeth Cobb (College Librarian and Head Instructor)
1926-1940 Martha Caroline Pritchard (First Chairman)
1941-1948 Esther Stallman (Acting Chairman 1940-1941)
1948-1961 Robert S. Burgess (Advising library science educators in Korea 1958-1961)
1958-1961 H. Carolyn Howard (Acting Chairman in Burgess' absence)
1961-1966 Irving A. Verschoor (First Dean)
1966-1967 Edgar W. Flinton (Acting Dean)
1967-1977 John J. Farley
1977-1978 Robert S. Burgess (Acting Dean)
1978-1981 Ben-Ami Lipetz
1981-1993 Richard Halsey
1993-1995 Richard P. Nathan (Acting Dean)
1995-2003 Phillip Eppard (Acting Dean 1995-1997)
2003-2005 Peter A. Bloniarz
2005-2006 Carol A. Doll
2006-2007 Stephen DeLong (Interim Department Chair)
1967-1977 Terry Maxwell
2011-present Phillip Eppard
Scope and Contents
These records document the administrative, curricular, and social activities of the Department of Information Studies from its establishment as a one year undergraduate school for librarians in 1926 through the early part of the twenty-first century. The bulk of the records, which consist of correspondence, meeting minutes, memoranda, annual reports, accreditation reports, and course outlines and syllabi were created between 1926 and 1990.
Arrangement of the Collection
The collection is organized into five topical series.
Higher Education Administration; Library Education; Professional Education; Library Schools; Information Science; Web Archives; UAlbany Academic Departments; State University of New York at Albany; State University of New York at Albany. Department of Information Studies; State University of New York at Albany. School of Information Science and Policy; Martha Caroline Pritchard; Esther Stallman; Irving A. Verschoor; John J. Farley; Robert S. Burgess; Ben-Ami Lipetz; Richard Halsey
- Administration and Faculty, 1912-2001; 1; 6.9 cubic ft.
  Conditions Governing Access
  Seven files contain personally identifiable information and are restricted.
  Scope and Contents
  This series contains correspondence, meeting minutes, annual reports, memoranda, enrollment statistics, inventories, and other records that pertain to the administration and faculty of the Department of Information Studies and its past iterations. This series documents routine activities such as internal and external faculty and departmental correspondence, faculty meetings, admission information, curriculum development, annual reports, grants and fellowships offered through the department, special projects conducted, and enrollment statistics. Prominent dates include the foundation of the Library School (1926), the development of the Master’s Program (1949-1950) and later the Doctorate Program (1968-1971), the school's union with Rockefeller College (1986).
  - Academic Affairs Office, 1971-1976; 1980-1984 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Academic Programs - Curriculum, 1964-1967; 1969-1975; 1978-1980; 1982-1983; Undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Academic Programs - BA/MLS, 1982-1983 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Academic Programs - Departmental/Goals Report (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Academic Programs - Doctoral Programs, 1964-1973; Undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Academic Programs - Field Work-RESTRICTED, 1930-1942; 1949-1959; 1961-1962; Undated (Box 1, Folder 6)
    May contain personally identifiable information. Please contact an archivist for more details.
  - Academic Programs - Five Year Plan [1 of 2], 1981-1983 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Academic Programs - Five Year Plan [2 of 2], 1981-1983 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Academic Programs - Graduate Programs, 1961-1967; 1983-1984 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Academic Program - International Comparative Librarianship (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Academic Programs - Librarianship Trainee Program - A Kirwin, 1970-1973; Undated (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Academic Programs - Medical Courses (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Academic Programs - New Courses [1 of 2], 1963-1967; 1969-1985; Undated (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Academic Programs - New Courses [2 of 2], 1963-1967; 1969-1985; Undated (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Academic Programs - Off-Campus Course Offerings [1 of 2], 1962-1970; 1978-1979; Undated (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Academic Programs - Off-Campus Course Offerings [2 of 2], 1962-1970; 1978-1979; Undated (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Academic Programs - Questionnaires, 1982-1983 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Academic Programs - Registered Courses (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Academic Programs - SUNY Library Research Center, 1972-1974; Undated (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Academic programs - Undergraduate Pilocy Manual (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Academic Programs - Undergraduate Programs [1 of 2], 1962-1963; 1965-1966; 1979-1984; Undated (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Academic Programs - Undergraduate Programs [2 of 2], 1962-1963; 1965-1966; 1979-1984; Undated (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Academic Programs - Vetran Administration Hospital Internships, 1976-1977; Undated (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Academic Standing Committee (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Acceptance Letters - Standard, 1975-1985 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Account Numbers/Titles (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Adler helen (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Admission Stanards, 1930-1937; 1941-1943; 1955-1956 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Admission Standards for Other Doctoral Programs (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Admission Committee (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Advisory Council, 1975-1978 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Affirmative Action, 1976-1982 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Albany Librarian Trainee Program, 1970-1973 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Allocation of Resources, Undated (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Alumni Newsletter (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Annual Reports, 1926-1927; 1941-1942; 1944-1956 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Annual reports, 1968-1978 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Annual Reports, 1979-1981 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Annual Reports, 1982-1983; 1985; 1987 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Annual Reports of Dean, 1967-1973 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Annual Reports of Dean, 1975-1978 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Annual Report of Dean, 1979-1981 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Application Information, 1983-1984; Undated (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Application - Rejected ( Examples Only), 1939; 1941-1942; 1948; 1953 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Archives, 1975; 1981 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Aslan Student Report, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Awards, 1966; 1970; 1976-1978 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Bachelor of Arts/ Master of Library Science Program, 1983 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Baker, Catherine Mills Love, 1920-1938 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Beard, Sarah, 1955-1958 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Behymer, Hugh, 1954-1959 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Bindery, 1945-1951 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Board of Regents Rules, 1926 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Book Sales, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Budget, 1926; 1928-1930; 1934; 1937-1948 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Burgess, Robert, 1950-1958 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Butler, Helen, 1939-1940 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Faculty By-Laws of School of Library Science, 1966; 1968; 1974; 1976; 1983 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Career Advancement Newsletter, 1979 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Catalog, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Catalog - Interim, 1986 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Catalog, Supplementory Materials, 1984-1985 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Cebrat, Anna, 1956-1957; 1959-1960; Undated (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Certificate of Proficiency, Undated (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Certificate Program - Proposal, 1977 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Christmas Letters to Alumni - Department of Librarianship, 1927-1944 (Oversized 2, Item 1)
  - Civil Service, 1962-1964; 1972-1975; 1978; 1980; Undated (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Clarkson, Marguerite, 1956-1957 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Clerical, 1964; 1967-1970; 1972; 1980 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - College Book Exchange, 1951-1952 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Collins, Evans - President, 1957; 1961-1965; Undated (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Colloquia, 1969-1973; 1976-1979; 1981; 1983-1984; Undated (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Commencement, 1973-1974; 1976; 1982-1986 (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Committee, Ad Hoc re: Course Development/Revision, 1982-1984; Undated (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - The Committee (SLIS) (1 of 3), 1972 (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - The Committee (SLIS) (2 of 3), 1972 (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - The Committee (SLIS) (3 of 3), 1972 (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - Committee - University Day, 1972-1975; 1979; Undated (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - Conferences and Meetings - 1971 Colloquium, 1971-1972 (Box 2, Folder 42)
  - Conferences and Meetings - 1972 Colloquium, 1971-1972 (Box 2, Folder 43)
  - Conferences and Meetings - 1973 Colloquium (Box 2, Folder 44)
  - Conferences and Meetings - Systems Conference, 1962; 1965 (Box 2, Folder 45)
  - Conference on Education for Information Science - Strategies for Change in Library School Program, 1977 (Box 2, Folder 46)
  - Connor, Jean, 1963-1964 (Box 2, Folder 47)
  - Continuing Education, 1978-1980; 1982 (Box 2, Folder 48)
  - Continuing Professional Education - Market Survey, 1977-1978 (Box 2, Folder 49)
  - Cook, Esther, 1962; 1964-1965 (Box 2, Folder 50)
  - Course Development Survey, 1977 (Box 2, Folder 51)
  - Course Schedules, 1947 (Box 2, Folder 52)
  - Course Schedules, 1972-1979; 1981; 1983-1985 (Box 2, Folder 53)
  - Credit Transfer Requests, 1926-1929; 1932; 1935; 1951; Undated (Box 2, Folder 54)
  - Curriculum Change, 1949; 1951; 1956; 1958; Undated (Box 2, Folder 55)
  - Curriculum Committee, 1965-1967; 1970 (Box 2, Folder 56)
  - Curriculum Committee, 1971-1977 (Box 2, Folder 57)
  - Curriculum Committee, 1978 (Box 2, Folder 58)
  - Curriculum Committee, 1979 (Box 2, Folder 59)
  - Curriculum Committee, 1980; 1982-1983 (Box 2, Folder 60)
  - Curriculum Development, 1914-1915; 1928-1929; 1931-1933 (Box 2, Folder 61)
  - Curriculum Development, 1935-1942; 1947; 1957 (Box 2, Folder 62)
  - Curriculum - Official Rulings, 1932; 1934-1943; 1945-1947; 1950; Undated (Box 2, Folder 63)
  - Curriculum Standards, 1927; 1929; 1933; 1940-1941; 1945-1948 (Box 2, Folder 64)
  - Curriculum Statements, 1971-1972; Undated (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Curriculum - Surveys, 1926-1927; 1936-1937; 1939 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Dean, Dr. Hazel, 1958; Undated (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Dean Search - Faculty Report *Restricted*, 1969 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Dean's Committee on Faculty Workload, 1975 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Deeringer, Dr.Jack - Associate Dean for Administrative Affairs, 1958; 1962-1965 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Delphi Study, 1971 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Department Manual - Department of Librarianship (Oversized 2, Item 2)
  - Department Manuals - Courses, 1959-1961 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Department Manuals - Field Work, 1959-1961; Undated (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Department Manuals - Miscellaneous, 1943-1944; 1946-1948; 1960; 1974; Undated (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Department Manuals - Old Manual, Undated (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Department Manuals - Purpose of Department, 1960 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Department Goals Report, 1972; 1977 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Departmental Objectives, 1934; 1939; 1946; 1951; Undated (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Department Reports - Department of Librarianship, 1926-1946 (Oversized 2, Item 3)
  - Department Reports - Department of Librarianship, 1946-1956 (Oversized 2, Item 4)
  - Departmental Support Accounts, 1982 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Directories, 1980-1982 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Disabled Student Services, 1972; 1978; 1980-1981; Undated (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Ditzion, Dr. Sidney, 1949-1956; Undated (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Doctoral Program Proposal, 1968-1971 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - East Campus, 1979-1985; Undated (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Eaton, Thelma, 1932-1938; 1941-1942; 1944; 1948; Undated (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Education in Librarianship Account Expenditure Information 320-06727, 1975 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Employeement Letters, 1957-1958 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Enrollment Profiles, 1971-1974; 1976; 1980; Undated (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Enrollment - Regular Session, 1927-1929; 1931-1933; 1935-1942; 1951 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Enrollment - Summer Session, 1931-1939; Undated (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Equal Opportunity Compliance, 1971-1973; Undated (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Equipment ( 1 of 2), 1967-1968; 1973; 1975-1977; 1979-1987; Undated (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Equipment ( 2 of 2), 1967-1968; 1973; 1975-1977; 1979-1987; Undated (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Extension Courses, 1954-1956 (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Faculty By-Laws, 1966; 1983 (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - Faculty Committees List, 1964-1965 (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - Faculty Death News Release, 1986 (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - Faculty Development Committee, 1974-1983; Undated (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - Faculty Directory, 1972 (Box 3, Folder 35)
  - Faculty Division of Responsibilty, 1930 (Box 3, Folder 36)
  - Faculty Evaluations, 1975 (Box 3, Folder 37)
  - Faculty - FTE/Workload, 1971 (Box 3, Folder 38)
  - Faculty - Hiring Policies, 1979 (Box 3, Folder 39)
  - Faculty-Leave Accrual, 1979 - 1983 (Box 3, Folder 40)
  - Faculty Meeting Minutes, 1936; 1956-1959; Undated (Box 3, Folder 41)
  - Faculty Meeting Minutes, 1965-1966 (Box 3, Folder 42)
  - Faculty Meeting Minutes, 1969-1975 (Box 3, Folder 43)
  - Faculty Meeting Minutes, 1976-1977 (Box 3, Folder 44)
  - Faculty Meeting Minutes "The Committee", 1972; Undated (Box 3, Folder 45)
  - Faculty Memoranda ( 1 of 3), 1970-1977; 1979; 1981; Undated (Box 3, Folder 46)
  - Faculty Memoranda ( 2 of 3), 1970-1977; 1979; 1981; Undated (Box 3, Folder 47)
  - Faculty Memoranda ( 3 of 3), 1970-1977; 1979; 1981; Undated (Box 3, Folder 48)
  - Faculty News, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 49)
  - Faculty Retirement Party, 1985 (Box 3, Folder 50)
  - Faculty Retreat, 1969-1970 (Box 3, Folder 51)
  - Faculty Retreat, 1973 (Box 3, Folder 52)
  - Faculty Retreat, 1984 (Box 3, Folder 53)
  - Faculty Retreats, 1970-1975; Undated (Box 3, Folder 54)
  - Faculty Self-Report, 1973 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Faculty Statement on the Future of Library School, ca. 1970; 1972 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Faculty Vacancies, 1985-1986 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Faculty - Weekly Newsletter, 1977-1979 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Fellowships - 20-0672A (Whalen), 1975 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Fellowships - 320-0819A (Whalen), 1972-1973; 1979; Undated (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Fellowships - 320-0819B, 1978; 1981; Undated (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Fellowships - 320-0921A (Lipetz), 1979; Undated (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Fellowships - 320-1284A, 1984 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Fellowships - 320-1359A, 1985 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Fellowships - 320-1449A, 1986 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Field Trips ( 1 of 6), 1932-1943; 1946; 1950-1963; Undated (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Field Trips ( 2 of 6), 1932-1943; 1946; 1950-1963; Undated (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Field Trips ( 3 of 6), 1932-1943; 1946; 1950-1963; Undated (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Field Trips ( 4 of 6), 1932-1943; 1946; 1950-1963; Undated (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Field Trips ( 5 of 6), 1932-1943; 1946; 1950-1963; Undated (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Field Trips ( 6 of 6), 1932-1943; 1946; 1950-1963; Undated (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Flinton, Dr. Edgar, 1961-1965 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Floor Plan, 1973; 1977 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Founder's Day, 1932-1933; 1935-1941 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Freiser, Leonard, 1958-1961 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Funk and Wagnalls - 320-1161A (Halsey), 1982 (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Galick, V. Genevieve, 1963-1964 (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Gambee, Budd, RESTRICTED, 1957-1964 (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - Gilmour, Madeline RESTRICTED, 1926-1942; 1949 (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - Grants, Awards, Honors (Oversized 1, Folder 1)
  - Guest Speakers, 1929; 1936; 1938; 1950; 1964-1970 (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - Guest Speakers, 1972; 1974-1975; 1977-1979; 1984; Undated (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - Hawley Library, 1980; 1983; 1987 (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - Heller, Frieda, 1941-1942; Undated (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - Honoraries, 1978-1980 (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - Indonesian Fellowships Program, 1960-1961 (Box 4, Folder 31)
  - Institute Proposals - Burgess, 1975 (Box 4, Folder 32)
  - Institute, 1965; 1968; 1974-1975; 1977; 1985 (Box 4, Folder 33)
  - Institutional Research Office, 1978-1980; 1983 (Box 4, Folder 34)
  - Internship Program - State Libraries, 1983 (Box 4, Folder 35)
  - Inventory, Undated (Box 4, Folder 36)
  - Job Orders ( 1 of 2), 1971-1972; 1976; 1978-1987; Undated (Box 4, Folder 37)
  - Job Orders ( 2 of 2), 1971-1972; 1976; 1978-1987; Undated (Box 4, Folder 38)
  - Katz, William, 1981; 1983-1984; 1986; Undated (Box 4, Folder 39)
  - Keen, Margaret, 1949-1950; 1952-1956; 1959 (Box 4, Folder 40)
  - Kennedy, Anna Clark, 1927-1928; 1946-1947; 1950-1951; 1954 (Box 4, Folder 41)
  - Letters to the Alumni - Department of Librarianship, 1947-1960 (Oversized 2, Item 5)
  - Lewis, James - Assistant to the President, 1962-1965 (Box 4, Folder 42)
  - Librarian Certification Requirements, 1933-1936; 1938; 1940-1941; 1950; 1953 (Box 4, Folder 43)
  - Librarian Certification Requirements, 1958; Undated (Box 4, Folder 44)
  - Librarian Recruitment Campaign, 1944; 1946-1947; 1953-1954; Undated (Box 4, Folder 45)
  - Library Collection, 1969 (Box 4, Folder 46)
  - Library Committee, 1971; Undated (Box 4, Folder 47)
  - Library Evaluation, 1973; Undated (Box 4, Folder 48)
  - Library Instructions Materials File, 1977 (Box 4, Folder 49)
  - Library Inventory, 1960; Undated (Box 4, Folder 50)
  - Library Inventory of Missing Books, 1940; 1954-1955 (Box 4, Folder 51)
  - Library Materials Inventory, 1980 (Box 4, Folder 52)
  - Library Media Specialist Certification, 1971; Undated (Box 4, Folder 53)
  - Library of Congress Intern Program, 1976-1979 (Box 4, Folder 54)
  - Library Relocation, 1978 (Box 4, Folder 55)
  - Library School Newsletter, Undated (Box 4, Folder 56)